First...
初　初夜
First night...
F-Finally under the same roof with Tabuki.
ついに多蕗さんと一つ屋根の下
Our first night together.
初めての夜を
多蕗さんと初めての夜
My first night with Tabuki.
That's the first night.
それが初夜　もうすぐよ
Soon...
Then, there's Project M.
そしてその先にはプロジェクトMが
When it's complete, our fates will be bound together.
これさえ完成させれば
私たちの運命は繋がる
So...
だから
First night!
初夜
<< kurukuru mawaru kimi no hitomi >>
<< Round and round, your eyes wander around >>
くるくる回る
君の瞳探して回る
<< sagashite mawaru eki no home >>
<< Searching around the station's platforms >>
駅のホーム
<< hibiku fanfare >>
<< The sound of fanfare from afar >>
響くファンファーレ
<< garagara oto wo tateru machi >>
<< The clamorous city making noise >>
ガラガラ音を立てる街
<< toriaezu mimi wo kashite ita no >>
<< I tried to keep an ear out for all this >>
とりあえず耳を貸してみたの
<< mousugu kieru hazu no sekai ni >>
<< In a world that's about to end >>
もうすぐ消えるはずの世界に
<< gomen ne >>
<< I'm sorry >>
御免ね
<< mou nido to aenai youna sonna ki ga shite >>
<< I just had a feeling I would never see you again >>
もう二度と会えないようなそんな気がして
<< unmei ga warau >>
<< Fate is laughing at us >>
運命が笑う
<< rinkaiten toppa shiten da >>
<< I'm already past the point of no return >>
臨界点突破してる
<< genkai nara sude ni satte >>
<< Far over my limit >>
限界なら既に去って
<< zettaiteki shihai datte >>
<< Even your absolute control has >>
絶対的支配だって
<< houkai >>
<< Crumbled >>
崩壊
<< shuumatsu riron wa kijou no kuuron shika naitte >>
<< "The end of the world is nothing but a hypothesis" >>
終末理論は机上の空論でしかないって
<< 0 to 1 no sekaisen no hate kara sakebu yo >>
<< Is what I'm crying out from other side of the binary world line >>
ゼロとイチの世界線の果てから
叫ぶよ
<< mou sugu kimi ga ai ni kuru you na ki ga shite >>
<< I have a feeling you'll come see me soon >>
もうすぐ君が会いにくるような気がして
<< boku wa me wo tojiru yo >>
<< So I will be waiting with my eyes closed >>
僕は目を閉じるよ
本字幕由诸神字幕组(kamigami.org)制作,仅供学习交流之用
若您喜欢本作品,请支持正版影像制品
---诸神字幕组---
日听 xHunter  翻译：小音  校对：凌可乐
时间轴：绯桜闲   压制：笑眯眯的妖精
To'oh General Hospital
Who are you?
誰
Who am I?
誰って
Asami...
阿佐美
Are you a fan of mine, by any chance?
もしかしてファンの人
You'll have to arrange a meeting through my agent.
困ります　ちゃんと事務所通してくれないと
Asami, don't tell me you...
阿佐美　まさかお前
馴れ馴れしく呼ばないで　人を呼ぶわよ
Don't act like you know me!
I'll call for help!
Wait...
I know the item you're looking for.
Where's your brother?
お兄さんは
I can't get ahold of him.
それが　捕まらなくて
You two are so useless.
使えない兄弟ね
What do you mean useless?
使えないって何だよ
Today's
Slogan
You're the one who called us out without notice.
そちが急に呼び出しておいて
Watch out for the painful trap by your feet.
Let's be clear.
いい　この間みたいに日記を盗み読んだら
If you try to peek into my diary again, or try to take it from me by force...
力尽くで私から奪おうとした時は
I know.
分かってるよ　その場で焼却処分するって言うだろう
Peeled Chestnuts
You'll tear me up on the spot, right?
This is something I can't budge on, even for Himari.
いくらひまりちゃんのためだからって
Failure is not an option for the mission I'm about to carry out.
これだけは譲れない
これからやろうとする計画は　絶対に失敗出来ない
The mission?
計画
プロジェクトM　最大の試練だわ
Project M.
It's my greatest challenge.
"Project M"?!
プロジェクトM
Don't tell me "M" stands for marriage...
Mって　まさかマリッジ　結婚のMとか
"M" as in tying the knot?
Are you going to help me or not?
手伝うの　手伝わないの
手伝うよ　手伝えばいいんだろう
I will.
Peeled Chestnuts
Are you happy now?
Then, carry this first.
じゃ　まずはこれを運んで
What's this? Are you moving?
何これ　引っ越し
You're so pathetic.
だらしないわね　もっとシャキッと持ちなさいよ
Carry it like a man!
I'll kill you if you drop anythi-
言っとくけど　落としたら承知しないから
馬鹿
Idiot!
Why did you suddenly do that for?!
何するだよ　いきなり
You just stepped on Kappy and Ottie!
あなた今カタンとラちゃんを踏んだでしょう
Huh?
ええ
I'm sorry!
御免ね　痛かったよね
That must have hurt!
Don't tell me, you're taking those too?
もしかして　それも持っていくの
They're family, so of course we'll always be together.
この子たちは家族なんだから　いつも一緒に決まってるでしょう
Family, huh?
家族かね
It's common sense.
基本的なことでしょう
Okay, let's go!
さあ　出発
This is it.
ここよ
I knew it.
やっぱり
Why are you resting?
何休んでのよ
Move it, move it!
ほら　退いて　退いて
Get out of my way!
邪魔　邪魔
We'll hide them here for now.
とりあえずこうして隠しておくのよ
Um... isn't this Mr. Tabuki's apartment?
あのさ　ここで　多蕗先生のアパートだよね
だから
So?
Well, I remember it from the contact form...
ほら　学校の名簿ってさ
It's in my neighborhood too...
近所だから　なんとなく覚えてる
You'll obey me in exchange for letting you borrow my diary.
日記を貸す代わりに　私の言うことに黙って従い
Isn't that what you said?
あなたそう言ったわよね
Yes, but...
そうだけど
Then get right to work!
だったらきりきり働いて　まだ荷物はなるんだから
There's still plenty of luggage left.
What?
We're moving everything!
全部運ぶの　今日の夕方までにね
By end of the day.
What?!
Which one of you sent me the email?
どっちだよ　メール送ったのは
This is an unacceptable form of harassment.
嫌がらせにも程があるぞ
Like I said I, like, don't know!
だから知らないって言ってるじゃない
That address doesn't belong to either of us.
送り主のアドレス　私たちじゃないでしょう
There are a bunch of ways around it...
そんなもん　いくらだって
Oh, there must be someone pulling the strings behind the scenes.
そうか　裏で糸を引いてる奴がいるだな
I hope you know they're far more dangerous than you think!
いいか　そいつらはお前らが思ってよりずっと危険な連中なんだぞ
Even Asami was...
阿佐美だって
Did something happen to Kuho?
久宝さんがどかしたの
N-Nevermind.
いいや
By the way, she told us you got a new girlfriend again?
そういえば　久宝さんから聞いたよ　また新しい彼女出来たって
Don't change to topic.
そんな話じゃなくて
I heard about it too.
私もそれ聞いた
誰よその女
Who's this bitch?
Hey, cut it out alread-
おい　いい加減にしろよ
Hey, are you listening?
ね　もう聞いてんの
Spit it out.
白状しなさい
Which school is she from?
何処の学校の子なの
Tell-
H-Huh?
あっ　あれ
何それ
What's that?
Bird poop?!
鳥ランチー食らった
Isn't it too big to be...
デカ過ぎ　じゃね
あ　あれ
Huh?
Who's there?
誰だ
Rip to see inside
Exclusive
Super Bonus!
Too hot
Ka...n...ba...
冠　葉　君
How could you?
ひどいよ
好きなのは　私だけって言ったじゃん
I'm the only one.
You love.
You said.
That's a lie.
嘘よ　本命は私
I'm the one he really loves.
You're such an annoying woman.
アンタずうずうしい
What about you?
そっちこそ　頭悪いんじゃないの
Are you retarded?
Are you, you, you you you you...
You you you you you NO!
What, what on earth?!
嫌だ　何それ
What on, on, on on on on on...
on on on on on what!
嫌だわ　早くすり潰さないと
Oh no, I must crush him soon.
I'm beat!
疲れた
Hey! Who said you could rest?
ちょっと　誰が休んでいいって言ったの
How many trips have we made already?
だってもう何往復目だよ
もう　時間がないんだから
Sheesh, we have no time.
My new home must be completed by tonight.
夜までに新居を完成させないと
何だよ　新居って
What do you mean by "new home"?
いいから　さっさと立ちなさい
Just stand up!
Come on, stand!
ほら　立って　ね　立ちなさいってば
No, I really can't.
Stand up already!
本当に無理
Hmm?
H-Hey...
ちょっと　何だよ
What are you doing?
初　初　初夜
First night...
Tonight's the first night...
今夜は初夜
I have to feel his sleeper's breath on my skin.
息をそばに感じなきゃいけない
じゃ　初夜
The first night!
Stop!
やめて
I'm home!
ただいま
I-It's not what you think.
ち　違います
T-This is...
あのう　これは　いまは　たま　この態勢ですが
We just happen to be in this position now...
Hey, get away from me already!
おい　いい加減離れろって
あれ　大変だ
Huh?
Oh, no!
She's got a fever.
熱が
ママ　おしっこ
Mommy, I have to pee.
私のせいだって言うの
Are you saying it's my fault?
違う　ただこれは新しいスタート
No, I'm just saying we should have a new start!
スタート
Start?
ああ　リンゴだって　もういろいろな事が分かる年頃だ
Yeah.
Ringo is starting to understand things.
Isn't it sad that her birthday will always fall on Curry Day?
いつまでも誕生日がカレーの日じゃ可哀相だろう
But tomorrow is Momoka's...
でも明日は桃君の
ああ　命日だよ
Yeah, the anniversary of her death.
But it's also Ringo's birthday!
だが明日はリンゴの誕生日でもあるだぞ
So what?
それが何
It's our duty as parents to remember Momoka forever!
桃果の事をいつまで覚えておくのが親の勉めでしょう
Remembering and dwelling on it are two different things!
覚えてることと引きずるってことは別だ
It won't make anyone happy!
そんなんじゃ誰も幸せにならない
Open your eyes!
いい加減　目を覚ませ
嫌よ　桃果を忘れるなんて　嫌
No, I won't forget Momoka!
No!
We still have Ringo!
俺たちにはリンゴがいるじゃないか
We'll pour our love for Momoka into Ringo.
リンゴを桃果の分まで愛してやる
Curry Day
Birthday
Isn't that what we agreed on five years ago?
五年前そう決めただろう
I can't. Ringo isn't Momoka.
無理よ　リンゴは桃果とは違う
But you're still Ringo's mother!
それでも　君はリンゴの母親じゃないかああああ
Take this.
よっしょ　運命なんだ
It's fate!
Fate?
運命　そんなの残酷よ
That's too cruel!
Gangster of the sea - Moray eel
I'm a moray eel.
That's our fate.
これが俺たちの運命なんだ
We'll never move on until we accept that.
それを受け入れない限りに前へ進めないんだ
Is that all we can do?
ただ受け入れるしかないの
That will tear our family apart!
それじゃ私たち家族はバラバラよ
漂流よ
We're drifting apart!
わたし知ってるよ
I know what "fate" is.
運命が何かって
If I can become my sister, Momoka...
私が桃果お姉ちゃんと同じになれば
Mommy and Daddy won't fight, right?
パパとママは喧嘩しないよね
We won't split up, right?
ばらばらになんかならないよね
We'll be together as family, right?
ずっとずっと家族一緒にいられるんだよね
Ringo - 6 Years Later - Oginome House, Living Room - *On that Curry Day, Tabuki talked about the cat, and my "destiny" was decided.
Curry Day
Don't hold back. Eat as much as you want!
遠慮せず　沢山食べてて頂戴ね
I will, thank you.
はい　ありがとうございます
Keiju, thank you for being Momoka's friend.
桂樹君　いつまでも桃果の友達でいてくれてありがとう
Don't mention it.
いいえ　そんな
桃果さんは僕の子供時代のすべてでした
Momoka was my everything as a child.
It was fate.
運命だったんです
You didn't have to walk me home.
わざわざ送ってくれなくでもいいのに
Ringo?
リンゴちゃん
多蕗さん
Tabuki.
My sister...
お姉ちゃんは　桃果はそんなに特別ですか
Momoka was that special?
Suginame Ward
Frog Park
Can you ride a bicycle?
リンゴちゃんは自転車に乗れる
うん
Yes.
What if I asked you to ride the bike like when you couldn't?
じゃ乗れなかった時と同じように今自転車に乗ってくれと言われたら
どうする
そんなの出来ないよ
I can't do that.
転じゃうし　それに
I would fall, and...
You've forgotten what it was like when you couldn't?
もう乗れなかった時のことを忘れてしまった
うん
Yes.
You could say I learned how to ride a bike thanks to Momoka.
例えると桃果のおかげで僕は自転車に乗れた
The feeling of cutting through the air, hearing the sound wind breeze by.
耳元で風が渦を巻いて
ぐいぐい空気を斬って進む感覚
The scenery changing at startling rate.
驚くぐらい早く流れていく景色
桃果は僕が見慣れていたはずの世界を一瞬で別の物に変えてくれた
Momoka changed my perspective of the world in a heartbeat.
The skies, birds, clouds, and even tiny pebbles...
空も鳥も雲も
足元に転がっている小さいな石ころでさえ
seemed like treasures filled with possibilities when I saw them with Momoka.
桃果と見れば
別の可能性を秘めた宝もののように見えた
But... I can't go back now.
でももうあの時には戻れないんだ
自転車には乗れる
I can still ride the bike.
Although, I can't recall what the treasures were.
けど何が宝ものだったのか　思え出せない
Sometimes I wonder why Momoka is no longer in this world.
時時　ふっと思うだ
どうしてこの世界には桃果がいないだろうかって
This world surrounding me now appear awfully uncertain to me right now.
僕を取り巻くこの世界が
今の僕にはひどく不確かに見える
Like Schrödinger's cat.
まるでシュレイデェガンの猫のように
Cat?
猫
A half-dead, half-alive cat.
半分死んでいて　半分生きてる猫
Poor cat.
その猫可哀相
On the other hand, if that's the fate's design...
でもね　それが運命の意図することなのだとしたら
きっとすべての事には意味がある
Then everything must have a meaning.
That's what I would like to think.
僕はそう思いたいんだ
Ringo's
The fate's design...
運命の意図すること
ginome Momoka
My sister, Momoka's diary.
お姉ちゃんの　桃果の日記
ginome Momoka
Oginome Momoka
I've finally realized.
やっと分かった
This mission must have a meaning.
このミッションにはきっと意味があるんだ
Write down the world's fate here.
ここに世界の運命を書く
When the future written here become true,
ここに書かれた未来が真実になる時
everything precious to me will become "eternal."
わたしの大切なものは永遠になるだろう
Takakura?
高倉
はい　高倉晶馬と言います
Yes, I'm Shoma Takakura.
What is it?
何か
ううん　まさかね
No, I thought just maybe...
I can't believe she passed out on the way home.
あの子だら下校中に倒れるなんて
But I'm glad a good boy like yourself happened to walk by.
でもよかったは
たまたま通りかかったのが高倉君みたいないい子で
いいや
Right...
So, how long have you and Ringo been dating?
って　リンゴとはいつから付き合ってるの
Geez, you don't have to hide it!
嫌だ　隠さなくてもいいのよ
I'm actually pretty frank as a mother, you know?
こう見えでも　結構フランクな母親なんだから
いいえ　リンゴさんとは　何と言うか
N-No, Ringo is...
How should I put it... just a friend...
ただの友達って言うか　妹がお世話になってものですから
She's pretty close with my younger sister.
Oh, that's no fun.
何だ　つまらないの
But it seems she's taken a liking to you.
でもあの子は高倉君のこと気に入ってるみたいよ
Maybe that uniform eases her mind even more.
その制服だと余計安心するのかしらね
What?
ううん　知り合いが先生やってでね
Well, we know this teacher...
Are you talking about Mr. Tabuki?
もしかして　多蕗先生ですか
Yes!
そう　知ってる
Do you know him?
Keiju Tabuki.
多蕗桂樹君
He's my homeroom teacher.
僕の担任です
Really?
そうなんだ
How do you know him?
あのう　知り合いって如何いう
Curry Day
Ringo's older sister was in his grade.
リンゴの姉がね　彼と小学校の同級生だったの
She has an older sister?
お姉さんがいるんですか
Although, she passed away a long time ago.
と言っても　もうずっと前に亡くなってしまったんだけどね
Ringo's
So... I have to become Momoka.
だから桃果にならなきゃ
That's my destiny.
それが私の運命
Mom, dad, and Tabuki...
パパもママも多蕗さんも
They must all be waiting...
きっと待ってる
for Momoka and I to become one.
私と桃果が一つになるのは
Then, everything precious to me will return.
そうすれば大切なものがみんな戻ってくるから
Survival Strategy!
生存戦略
Welcome to Rock'n Roll Night
Welcome to Rock'n Roll Fight
I'm just a Rock'n Roll MAN
I'm just a Rock'n Roll Man
We're just a Rock'n Roll BAND
We've been running down this road
俺たちは道なりに　歩き続けてきた
Racing through a path full of signs
標識だらけの道を飛ばし続けていく
We crossed countless towns, spreading our song
幾つもの町を抜け　歌い続けてきた
Continuing to torment these cowardly fools
腑抜け野郎共を煽り続けていく
The wind blows even after the lengthy winter
長い長い冬が溶けても風が吹く
Still storming down the road
今も今も激しく風が吹く
Imagine!
Listen, you lowlifes who will never amount to anything.
きっと何物にもなれないお前たちに告げる
Obtain the Penguin Drum.
ピングドラムを手に入れるのだ
No, it's impossible!
や　もう　無理無理
She was mumbling something about "the first night", and passed out from fever!
今日だって　初夜だとか言って　熱出して　ぶっ倒れて
Where's my bro?!
兄貴がいない
It's your job to carry out this so-called destiny,
運命とやらを成就させて　ピングドラムを奪うのが貴様らの役目だ
and snatch the Penguin Drum.
Do you understand?
よいか　初夜だろうと初交尾だろうと
I don't care if it's the first night or the first mating.
変態女の望み通りにさせてやれ
You'll let the pervert girl do what she wants.
Don't say such distasteful thing using Himari's mouth!
ひまりの口でそんな下品なことを言うな
Shut up, you weasel.
黙れ　外道
You're the weasel...
外道なのはそっちだろう
Taking my sister for a hostage.
人の妹を人質にとって
Weasel Knievel.
外道上等
Who still says that?!
今時ヤンキーかよ
それで古くねええええ
It's old as hell!
Let's initiate the Survival Strategy.
生存戦略　しましょうか
Kanba - Tragedy at Noon - Department Store Rooftop, Living Room
*Yui and Chizuru regains consciousness. But they've changed.
Hey, get yourself together!
おい　しっかりしろ
大丈夫よ
We're fine.
ところで　聞きたいんだけど
By the way, I've been wondering...
Who are you?
アンタ　誰
By the way, I've been wondering, too.
ところで　私も聞きたいんだけど
Who are you?
アンタ　誰
Ringo?
リンゴ　具合は如何
How are you feeling?
Let me know if you want anything.
何か欲しければ　声をかけてね
Sleep tight.
じゃ　お休み
The first night...
初夜　運命は変えられない
Fate cannot be altered.
My first night with Tabuki.
今夜　多蕗君と初めての夜
私は彼の寝息を　　マジかで感じるのだ
I'll feel his breath up close!
Making dinner together is our first joint task.
初めての共同作業は一緒に晩御飯を作ること
It's a little burned, but Tabuki praises me as usual, saying "it's delicious."
少し焦げじゃったけど
いつものように　多蕗君が美味しいと褒めてくれる
And so, our ordinary life together has begun.
こんな風に何気なく私たちの生活が始まった
Tonight, our souls will touch for the very first time.
今夜　彼と私はようやくお互いの本当の部分に触れるこのになるのだ
I bought new toothbrushes just for tonight.
今日のために　新しい歯ブラシも買った
The blue one for Tabuki.
多蕗君はブル　私はピンク
The pink one for me.
First Night in Progress
So, do you remember?
ね　多蕗さん
覚えてる全てのことに意味があるって言ったあの言葉
Those words, "everything must have a meaning."
I believe it.
私信じてるよ
Fate must be shaped like a gigantic ring.
運命ってさ
きっと物凄く大きな輪かな形をしているだよ
Tabuki and Momoka were suppposed to be together.
結ばれるはずだった多蕗さんと桃果
So, I'll become Momoka and rotate the frozen ring of fate.
だから　私が桃果になって
止まった運命の輪を回す
And when the future written in the diary comes true,
そして日記に書かれていた未来が真実になるとき
things precious to me will become "eternal."
私の大切なものは永遠になるのだ
Yes, that's right.
え　ええ　そう
Everything is going according to the plan.
すべては計画通りに進行中よ
Yes, I've made certain.
ええ　確認したわ
Fate's trajectory is in the palm of our hands.
運命の軌道は私たちの手のうちにある
I will set Project M into motion soon.
もうすぐ　プロジェクトMを発動するわ
You and I are Bound by M
subete ga moshi kimerarete tara
If everything was written in stone
全てが欲しい
繋がれたいたら
僕らはどうして
bokura wa doushite mogaku no darou
Why have we been resisting our fate?
もがくのだろう
sore wa kimi ja nai
It's not you
それは君じゃない
君のせいじゃない
kimi no sei ja nai
It's not your fault
苦しみはもう沢山なんだ
kanashimi wa mou takusan nanda
I've had enough misery
だからそうじゃない
dakara sou ja nai
You're mistaken
夢のままじゃない
ima no mama ja nai
Fate can be changed
上手く伝えきれないけど
umaku tsutaekirenai kedo
I can't explain it, but
Dear my future
Dear you future
Dear your future
Imagine!
その奇跡の力には代償が必要なんだ
Listen, you lowlifes who will never amount to anything.
君はそれを分かってるのか
でも僕はやるよ　ひまりのために
Obtain the Blu-Ray.
本字幕由诸神字幕组(kamigami.org)制作,仅供学习交流之用
若您喜欢本作品,请支持正版影像制品
---诸神字幕组---
日听 xHunter  翻译：小音  校对：凌可乐
时间轴：绯桜闲   压制：笑眯眯的妖精
Let's initiate the Survival Strategy.
The power of miracle requires a price.
Do you understand?
生存戦略　外道上等
But I will do it.
For Himari.
I'm taller
than you––
Hmph
Lily Hoshino
Survival Strategy, Weasel Knievel.